# **Richard Eldridge**

### **SUMMARY:**

Software Developer with 2 years full stack experience. Highly skilled and knowledgeable at scripting, creating high functioning user-interfaces. refactoring inefficient code, and object-oriented-programming. Diverse experience with numerous API integrations, creating multiple subsystems, and modernizing Well-versed professional communication, in troubleshooting complex problems, working with remote team members, and e-commerce business operations.

### **CONTACT:**

Richardaeld@gmail.com

**Projects Website** 

GitHub LinkedIn

### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

## Atlanta Network Technologies (antonline)

Smyrna, GA | Jun 2022 - Present

Software Developer I

### System Design

 Designed, created, implemented, and maintained sub-systems for logistics and marketplace inventory integration. Reduced code volume by 60% and increased code readability.

#### Extend Infrastructure

- Created a Linux and PHP solution to maintain data integrity by ensuring scripts run only 1 instance at a time.
- Employed Object-Oriented-Programing (OOP) to unify front and back-end code of internal logistics interfaces. Increased readability and decreased code complexity and maintenance time by 80%.
- Designed and implemented an API that allowed JavaScript to utilize and call PHP classes and functions through the JS Fetch API.

### **API Integration & Maintenance**

• Implemented and updated 3rd party API integrations using PHP scripts with Model-View-Controller (MVC) architecture. Reduced and maintenance time by 50% compared to legacy integrations.

### **Create and Maintain Reports**

- Developed a PHP API and new JavaScript architecture which enabled fully reactive reports. Reduced required code by 50%.
- Improved user experience and visual appeal of legacy reports by integrating JavaScript and updating CSS.
- Modernized and updated legacy reports by adding MVC and OOP architecture. Improved readability and decreased maintenance by 75%.

### **Monitor Logs**

Interpreted system logs to identify bugs and ensure optimal user experience.

# SGPS ShowRig, Inc.

Norcross, GA | Feb. 2015 - Jun 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control

## **SKILLS:**

### Languages

**JavaScript** Java PHP CSS / HTML Python

### Tools

Linux Git Docker Visual Studio Code Google Meet

### **Databases**

Percona MvSOL PostgreSQL Mongo DB

### Libraries

Node.is Express.js React.is

## **RECOGNITION:**

#### Hack-a-thon Awards

1st Place Award: 2022 3rd Place Award: 2021

### **Code Institute Projects** with Merit Distinction

Fat Raccoon Website Eldridge Music Emporium

### **EDUCATION:**

Software Development Diploma \*EU Accredited RQF Level 5 Diploma Code Institute

Kennesaw State University

**Bachelor's of Computer Science** 

In progress - Senior

May 2020 - Nov. 2021